[
    {
        "question": "When does Nepal Celebrate New Year?",
        "options": [
            "A. 1st Baisakh",
            "B. 2nd Baisakh",
            "C. 29th Chaitra",
            "D. 30th Chaitra"
        ],
        "answer": "A. 1st Baisakh"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nobel prize is awarded for which of the following disciplines?",
        "options": [
            "A. Literature, peace and economics",
            "B. Medicine or Physiology",
            "C. Chemistry and Physics",
            "D. All the above"
        ],
        "answer": "D. All the above"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many provinces are there in Nepal?",
        "options": [
            "A. 1",
            "B. 7",
            "C. 14",
            "D. 75"
        ],
        "answer": "B. 7"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country operationalized world\u00e2\u20ac\u2122s largest radio telescope?",
        "options": [
            "A. USA",
            "B. China",
            "C. Russia",
            "D. India"
        ],
        "answer": "B. China"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one among the following radiations carries maximum energy?",
        "options": [
            "A. Ultraviolet rays",
            "B. Gamma rays",
            "C. X- rays",
            "D. Infra-red rays"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Gamma rays"
    },
    {
        "question": "The head quarters of world trade organization is in?",
        "options": [
            "A. Montreal",
            "B. Seattle",
            "C. Geneva",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Geneva"
    },
    {
        "question": "The language spoken by the people by Pakistan is ?",
        "options": [
            "A. Hindi",
            "B. Nepali",
            "C. English",
            "D. Sindhi"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Sindhi"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the end of March 2019, what was the amount of India's external debt?",
        "options": [
            "A. US $ 540 billion",
            "B. US $ 543 billion",
            "C. US $ 547 billion",
            "D. US $ 541 billion"
        ],
        "answer": "B. US $ 543 billion"
    },
    {
        "question": "'LIBRA' an alternative of existing cryptocurrency like bitcoin is being developed by?",
        "options": [
            "A. Facebook",
            "B. Google",
            "C. Microsoft",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Facebook"
    },
    {
        "question": "Galileo was an astronomer who?",
        "options": [
            "A. developed the telescope",
            "B. discovered four satellites of Jupiter",
            "C. discovered that the movement of pendulum produces a regular time measurement",
            "D.  All the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. discovered four satellites of Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Headquater of International Olympic Committee is situated at?",
        "options": [
            "A. Athens",
            "B. Lausanne",
            "C. Dubai",
            "D. None of the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Lausanne"
    },
    {
        "question": "'The Coalition Years' is the autobiography of?",
        "options": [
            "A. L.K Advani",
            "B. Pranab Mukherjee",
            "C. Atal Behari Vajpayee",
            "D. Sonia Gandhi"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Pranab Mukherjee"
    },
    {
        "question": "The metal whose salts are sensitive to light is?",
        "options": [
            "A. Silver",
            "B. Zinc",
            "C. Copper",
            "D. Gold"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Silver"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the father of geometry?",
        "options": [
            "A. Aristotle",
            "B. Euclid",
            "C. Pythagoras",
            "D. Kepler"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Euclid"
    },
    {
        "question": "Entomology studies what?",
        "options": [
            "A. Behavior of human beings",
            "B. Insects",
            "C. The origin and history of technical and scientific terms",
            "D. The formation of rocks"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Insects"
    },
    {
        "question": "Galileo was an astronomer who",
        "options": [
            "A. Developed the telescope",
            "B. Discovered four satellites of Jupiter",
            "C. discovered that the movement of pendulum produces a regular time measurement",
            "D. All the above"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Discovered four satellites of Jupiter"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the father of geometry?",
        "options": [
            "A. Aristotle",
            "B. Euclid",
            "C. Pythagoras",
            "D. Kepler"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Euclid"
    },
    {
        "question": "Indian player Jude Felix is popular for which sports?",
        "options": [
            "A. Volleyball",
            "B. Football",
            "C. Hockey",
            "D. Tennis"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Hockey"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the current chief of the world bank group?",
        "options": [
            "A. Donald Tusk",
            "B. David Malpass",
            "C. Christine Lagarde",
            "D. Jim Yong Kim"
        ],
        "answer": "B. David Malpass"
    },
    {
        "question": "When was Second World War started?",
        "options": [
            "A. September 1, 1939",
            "B. September 1, 1940",
            "C. September 1, 1945",
            "D. September 1, 1942"
        ],
        "answer": "A. September 1, 1939"
    },
    {
        "question": "Each year World Red Cross and Red Crescent Day is celebrated on?",
        "options": [
            "A. May 8",
            "B. May 18",
            "C. June 8",
            "D. June 19"
        ],
        "answer": "A. May 8"
    },
    {
        "question": "The brain fever which affects young children is?",
        "options": [
            "A. Malaria",
            "B. Typhoid",
            "C. Encephalitis",
            "D. Pneumonia"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Encephalitis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which is the first search engine of the internet?",
        "options": [
            "A. Yahoo",
            "B. Wais",
            "C. Archie",
            "D. Mozilla"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Archie"
    },
    {
        "question": "In a Database Management System(DBMS) the content and the location of data is identified by ?",
        "options": [
            "A. Subdata",
            "B. Sequence Data",
            "C. Beta Data",
            "D. Meta Data"
        ],
        "answer": "D. Meta Data"
    },
    {
        "question": "'.MOV' extensions refer to which kind of file?",
        "options": [
            "A. Image file",
            "B. Movie File",
            "C. Audio File",
            "D. ZIP File"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Movie File"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the famous poem 'The Charge of the Light Brigade'?",
        "options": [
            "A. Lord Alfred Tennyson",
            "B. Christopher Marlowe",
            "C. Johannes Gutenberg",
            "D. Rene Descartes"
        ],
        "answer": "A. Lord Alfred Tennyson"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who founded Indian National Army(INA)?",
        "options": [
            "A. Netaji Subhas Chandra Bose",
            "B. Mohan Singh",
            "C. Rash Behari Bose",
            "D. Jatridranath Mukherjee"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Mohan Singh"
    },
    {
        "question": "The control of which state was handed over to british after marriage of King Charles 2 with portuguese princess in 1661?",
        "options": [
            "A. Cochin",
            "B. Bombay",
            "C. Surat",
            "D. Madras"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Bombay"
    },
    {
        "question": " Country that has the highest in Barley Production ?",
        "options": [
            "A. China",
            "B. India",
            "C. Russia",
            "D. France"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Russia"
    },
    {
        "question": "The World Largest desert is ?",
        "options": [
            "A. Thar",
            "B. Kalahari",
            "C. Sahara",
            "D. Sonoran"
        ],
        "answer": "C. Sahara"
    },
    {
        "question": "Guru Gopi Krishna is popular for which form of Indian dance?",
        "options": [
            "A. Bharatanatyam",
            "B. Kuchipudi",
            "C. Kathak",
            "D. Manipuri"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Kuchipudi"
    },
    {
        "question": "J.B. Dunlop is popular for which of the following inventions?",
        "options": [
            "A. Model airplanes",
            "B. Pneumatic rubber tire",
            "C. Rubber boot",
            "D. Automobile wheel rim"
        ],
        "answer": "B. Pneumatic rubber tire"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who built this project ?",
        "options": [
            "Aman",
            "Nutan",
            "Shyam",
            "Ram"
        ],
        "answer": "Aman"
    }
]